Matthew Leonard

Mattl.co 1152 Woodland Lane Evergreen, CO 80439 1 (303) 717-8269 MattLeonardCO@gmail.com

Professional Interests

Hey, I'm Matt Leonard and I love building great software. I recently graduated from CU Boulder with a degree in software engineering.

During my time at CU I worked as a Ruby on Rails developer for two startups, Kapost and InvitedHome. At these companies I was able to learn everything from migrating data between MySQL and Postgres to building my own front-end frameworks. Using my knowledge I also built an automated bike shop, Shift Suppliers LLC, and a music streaming site, Mvsic.

I've most recently begun exploring Meteor.js and other JavaScript frameworks, while still continuing to grow as a RoR developer.

When I'm not crunching code, you'll find me at Whistler downhill mountain biking, shredding fresh snow in the Rockies, scuba diving in the Caribbean or road-tripping across the country.

Skills

Software:

- Sublime Text 2
- Terminal
- Git/Github
- Photoshop
- Illustrator

Languages:

- Rails/Ruby
- HTML5
- CSS3 / SASS / Less
- Javascript / jQuery
- MySQL / Postgresql
- Objective-C

Work Experience

Kapost Boulder, CO

Kapost.com

Ruby on Rails/Frontend Development

Automated testing, continuous integration, spec coverage

Aug 2014 – Feb 2015

- Building well tested new features
- Refactoring legacy code into service objects

Invited Home, Boulder, CO

May 2013 – Aug 2014

InvitedHome.com

Ruby on Rails/Frontend Development

- Building complex web application features
- Assembling pixel-perfect HTML/CSS/jQuery webpages from PSD designs.

Shift Suppliers LLC, Boulder, CO

Nov., 2013 – June, 2014

www.shiftsuppliers.com

Owner / Business Automater

- Automated stock and product publishing to be done by a Ruby on Rails webscraper, scraped and updated/published 23,000 product every night.
- Developed marketing strategies and maintained customer relationships.
- Managed stock and logistics to make sure customer got products on time
- Setup legal entity and insured shop.

MattL, Boulder, CO

September, 2012 – Current

mattl.co

Owner / Web Developer

- Building Ruby on Rails web apps
- Building pixel-perfect Wordpress powered websites from PSD mockups.
- Consulting on the front-end development of websites.
- Setting up websites for clients using Wordpress Prebuilt Themes.

Webtrends Inc, Portland, OR

May, 2012 - Aug, 2012

Webtrends.com

Front-end Development Intern – Design Lab

- Paper prototyping client ideas into framework layouts that effectively convey analytic data.
- Turning PSD mockups into live HTML, CSS and JavaScript web interfaces utilizing modular techniques.

Education

University of Colorado, Boulder, CO

2010 - 2015

Computer Science

Evergreen High School, Evergreen, CO

2006 - 2010

High School Graduate, Honors

Personal Interests

- Website / Web App Development
- Cat II. Downhill Mountain Bike Racing University of Colorado at Boulder
- Cross Country Mountain Biking
- Telemark Skiing
- Scuba Diving